Mário Patrão

24th October 1984 mariopatrao@gmail.com +44 7999 061551 Flat 5 Hexham Lodge, 10-12 Mildmay Park, N1 4PG, London

Personal statement

I'm a web developer with more than 5 years' experience and for the last 19 months I have been working at CTN Communications.

At CTN I developed and maintained an Umbraco CMS we called Umbracast that we use to live stream and ondemand host companies webcast events. Companies like Unilever, GlaxoSmithKline, RSA, GM&T among others have a need to create private micro-websites that match their branding to show their webcast internally and externally.

Currently I'm looking to embrace a new challenge that will allow me to grasp new technologies, augment my know-how and work with different "mind-sets".

Key Skills

Web development

- JavaScript, Node.js, C#, Vb.Net, Asp.Net, MVC, Asp;
- HTML, Ajax, XML, JSON;
- SQL Server, T-SQL, MySQL;
- CSS, SASS;
- GIT, Microsoft Visual Studio, SQL Server Management Studio;
- Internet Information Services.

Methodologies

Agile, Waterfall

Personal skills

- Pro-active, flexible, problem solver, autonomous and focused;
- Good communication skills honed after multiple public presentations;
- Experienced in teamwork, gained while working small and medium sized teams;
- Ability to work under pressure;
- Very apt at integrating multicultural environments after working with persons from foreign countries during ERASMUS.

Work Experience

From December 2014

Web Developer at **CTN Communications**. CTN Communications is a creative agency based in London, specialising in Leadership Consulting, Film & Video, Digital and Events.

 Umbracast (C#, JavaScript, MySQL): Umbracast is a CMS I worked since day one at CTN Communications. It's an Umbraco CMS that allow us to create microwebsite to stream live events for different companies. From May 2012 until December 2014

Developer at **Element3 Software**. Element3 is a bespoke cross-platform software company, combining leading edge technology with a fully consultative approach to ensure that the client needs are identified, visualized and built. The main projects I work on were:

- SAMS (Vb.net, SQL and JavaScript): SAMS is a housing developers' end to end sales process tool. It allows sellers of newly developed properties to track every sale opportunity and leverage the maximum return from every enquiry. In this project I was one of the core developers and built both client and server side including all the SQL tables and procedures. I was asked also to write a restful API to provide some clients the connection needed to update their own products;
- **FileHound** (Vb.net, SQL and JavaScript): Filehound is a modern web based document manager. It's written to be responsive and fast. I was in charge of develop all the server side code needed to work smoothly with the extensive front end development needed for this project;
- MyHa (JavaScript): MyHa is a tenant portal offering features and services that stretch beyond the standard solutions offered by other residents' portal services.
 Originally written in .net I was asked to modernise this web portal by creating from scratch all the necessary client side to improve all the functionalities asked by the client.

From July 2010 until March 2012

Developer at **Planeta Virtual**. Planeta Virtual is a software house specialized in web solutions. Its main product is a web solution that is responsible for the human resources, accounting and CRM implemented in several companies. I was responsible for multiple projects through the whole development cycle. The main projects were:

- Take a City (Vb.net, SQL, Web Services and Windows Services): developed all
 the solutions responsible for the login and the email communication to the
 Website;
- **Bang Ac** (Asp and SQL): developed the bang solution to a new client Atlanticare and a new module, Read Inquirers that using a third party tool (Engine) was able to read the results of paper inquires on a regular scanner;
- **Back office** (Vb.net, Asp.net, and XML): designed the entire data base and develop a back office of a website for a travel agency;
- **Files Updater** (Vb.net, Asp.net): a stay resident that is responsible for updating files when a pen disk is inserted in the computer.

From June 2009 until May 2010

Developer trainee at **Planeta Virtual**, worked on:

- Bang Secure Locations (Vb.net, Asp and SQL): designed a new module to the bang solution, which main goal is to secure and record a log with all the clients' critical information (server passwords and users information) that was to be used by the Planeta Virtual network guys;
- **Bang Zv** (Vb.net, Asp and SQL): developed the bang solution for a new client Zona Verde and a new module, Read Inquirers which, using a third party tool (Engine), was able to read the results of the inquires on a regular scanner.

Education

From September 2002 until January 2009

 Graduation in Informatics Engineering on Faculty of Science and Technology of the University Fernando Pessoa of Oporto.

From September 2006 until July 2007

 Computer System Engineering at The Academy of Humanities and Economics in Lodz under the ERASMUS Program. Final grade of 15 out of 20. Principal subjects covered were network security and designing of computer networks.

From October 2005 until December 2005

 Webmaster/Web Design at Tecla (Formação Profissional). Final grade of 150 points out of 200. Principal subjects covered were development of websites and web security.

Languages

Portuguese (native), English (expert), Spanish (basic).

Hobbies

- Practice sailing from the age of 14 and participated in multiple international classes:
- I play the guitar and I like to skate.